-=TLF字幕组=- 分享创作之乐，共赏字幕之美
翻译：胖收儿 校对：Disenchanted 压制：cyf91
1895年
看是谁！
Peek-a-boo!
别别别，别，别
No, no, no, no, no.
我不是想吓你，我的小宝贝儿
I didn't mean to startle you, my little baby.
Shh, Shh, shh.
# 嘘，小吸血鬼，别哭叫 #
# 爸爸去把鸟儿的头咬掉 #
A-bitty goo-bah!
我要亲亲你的小屁屁
I vant to kiss your tush.
我要亲亲你的小屁屁！
I vant to kiss your tush!
很好，不过再建得大一点儿
Nice, but maybe a little more square footage.
我希望这儿能住很多怪物
I want a lot of monsters here.
我要抓住你，小梅薇思
I'm gonna get you, little Mavis.
我要抓住你
I'm gonna get you! Oy.
那外面是什么？
What out there?
我们永远都不能去那里
Oh, we never go out there.
永远
Ever.
“但哈里找到了他们，从他们的床下蹦出来”
"But Harry the Human found them and jumped out from under their bed."
- 我怕！ - “烧了他们的衣服…”
I'm scared! "And burned their clothes
“…咬他们的脚趾！”
and bit their toes!"
“还抢走他们的糖果！”
"And took their candy!"
别抢我的糖果
Don't take my candy.
小东西，你不需要害怕
Babyclaws, you don't need to be frightened.
我答应过你妈妈要永远保护你的
I promised your mommy I would protect you forever.
# 我漂亮的梅薇 #
#让我把麻烦事全都包揽#
# 那些人类很邪恶 #
# 所以你要跟爸爸在一起 #
# 要是人类想伤害你 #
# 我就说… #
# 因为你是爸爸的心肝儿 #
# 爸爸的宝贝儿 #
# 我是你的亲亲爸爸 #
就一弯腿，跳下来
Just bend the legs and push off.
相信我，小家伙
Trust me, mouse.
我会飞了！我会飞了！
Ha-ha! I can fly! I can fly!
看看你自己！
Look at you!
飞快点，宝贝儿，飞快点！
Faster, baby! Faster!
你做到了，我的小魔女！
Whoo-hoo! You got it, my little voodoo doll!
打扰，大人
Excuse me, sir.
怎么了？怎么了？
What? What?
我没事儿
Ow. I'm okay.
竣工了
It's ready.
看起来不错
Looks good.
只有怪物能进来吗？
Only monsters can get in?
没错
Oh, absolutely.
它相当隐蔽
It's hidden real nicely.
前面有四百英亩闹鬼的森林
You got 400 acres of haunted forest in front of you.
周边是不死亡灵的领地
You got the Land of the Undead on the perimeters.
人类只消看上一眼，便会拔腿就跑
Any humans daring to even look over there will run away real quick.
但当然，聪明起见
But, of course, be smart.
没有营火，也没有烽火台
No bonfires, no firework shows.
嗯嗯，不不，不要火，我知道，我知道
Yeah, yeah, no, no. No fire, I get it, I get it.
是时候了，我亲爱的玛莎
It's time, my darling Martha.
我们总说要为梅薇思建造的城堡
The place we always talked about for Mavis.
在这里没人可以伤害她
No one will ever harm her here.
精灵旅社
献礼日
不死亡灵
车上一团糟
Yeah, it's a mess back there.
欢迎来到精灵旅社！
Welcome to Hotel Transylvania!
从1898年起就无人类骚扰
Human-free since 1898.
你们的安全首选
Your safest destination.
拿好节目单
Take an itinerary.
为了我女儿明天的生日盛典…
I have personally designed a spectacular schedule of events,
…我亲自设计了一场盛大的演出
all leading to my daughter's birthday extravaganza tomorrow.
我们每年都盼着来呢，大人
We always look forward to coming every year, Count.
我们太喜欢这种安全感了
We enjoy the safety so much.
当然了，那正我们建城堡的目的
Of course. That's why we built it.
晚上好
Yes, good evening.
多谢，马蒂
Thank you, Marty.
你也很苍白
You look pale, as well.
阁下，阁下，阁下！
Sir, sir, sir!
管道出了点儿紧急状况
We have an urgent plumbing issue.
管道？来搞定
Plumbing? On it.
古力干先生！
Mr. Ghouligan!
348房间的马桶堵了
There is a clogged toilet in room 348.
没关系，人人都会肚子疼，大脚怪先生
It's okay. We all get stomach aches, Mr. Bigfoot.
孩子们，老实点
Hey, kids, reel it in.
你们折磨爸爸妈妈就够了
You're only supposed to make Mom and Dad miserable.
乖，乖，那样做对吗？
Now, now, is that any way to behave?
这是旅社，不是墓地
This is a hotel, not a cemetery.
抱歉，德古叔叔
Sorry, Uncle Drac.
德古！近来可好？
Drac! How are ya?
维恩，我的老伙计！
Wayne, my old friend!
早就对这个周末迫不及待了
Couldn't wait for this weekend.
每次都得花几天时间摆脱生日会后遗症
Always great to be out of the shadows for a couple days.
你们一家人真漂亮
The family looks beautiful.
我得来打扫一下
Let me just clean up their filth.
打扫房间！
Housekeeping!
弗兰基，伙计，看看你！
Frankie, my boy! Look at you!
还是把自己邮寄过来，小气鬼，嗯？
Still traveling by mail, Mr. Cheapo, huh?
不差钱
It's not a money thing.
我有飞机恐惧症，明白？
I have a plane phobia, okay?
那些引擎随时都可能…
I mean, at any moment, those engines could catch...
…起火！
Fire! Yeah, yeah.
“火不好”
"Fire bad."
我们知道
We know.
奥古斯都，榆木脑袋，拜托了！
Augustus, Porridge Head, come on!
那个像是科学怪人的脑袋吗？
Does that look like Frankenstein's head?
德古，老兄，你的披肩怎么了？
Hey, Drac, buddy, what's going on with your cape there?
你什么意思？哦！
What do you mean? Oh!
谁掐我？
Who pinched me?
真抱歉，你太迷人了
Guilty. You're irresistible.
是啊，很好笑嘛，隐形人
Yes, very amusing, Invisible Man.
你好，“见”到你真高兴
Hello. Great to "see" you.
这笑话还没讲够么
Never gets old.
Ho-ho-ho.
找不到我
Missed me.
找不到找不到找不到我
Missed me, missed me, missed me.
好的，你赢了，拿着这块培根
Okay, you win. Hold this bacon.
为什么要拿着培根…啊！
Why am I holding bacon... Ahh!
不！让他们走开！
No! Get 'em off!
聚会来咯！
Here comes the party!
你好，莫里！
Hello, Murray!
德古，怎么了，兄弟？
Drac, what's up, buddy?
沙子，莫里，沙子！
The sand, Murray, the sand!
总弄得到处都是沙子
Always with the sand.
Whee!
沃夫！旺达！弗兰克！
Wolfie! Wanda! Frank!
我喜欢这家伙
I love this guy.
他永远这么带劲
He always bringing it full tilt.
你看起来也很瘦
You're looking skinny, too.
因为你只有个头
Now that you're just a head.
好吧，你会为此付出代价的
Okay, you'll pay for that.
怎么了，德古？
So what's up, Drac?
旅社看起来乱作一团了
The hotel is looking off the hook.
嘿，伙计们，看着
Hey, guys, watch this.
另外，你告诉我的路线果然没错
By the way, you were right about those directions.
哦，不错，不错
Oh, good, good.
对，经由底格里斯河…
Yeah, I took the Tigris
…穿过尼罗河，路上都没堵
through the Nile, and there was absolutely no traffic.
你搞什么
You're kidding me.
在我的大厅里放屁？
Right in my lobby?
德古，我发誓，不是我干的
Drac, I swear, man, I don't run like that.
打扫房间！
Housekeeping!
真不是我干的
I was not the cause of that.
我们准备好了！
We're ready!
梅薇思生日快乐
要是玛莎能看到这些该多好
If only Martha were here to see this.
玛莎一直都在，旺达
She's always here, Wanda.
好了，朋友们
Okay, friends,
很高兴各位能来
I am so glad you are here to celebrate.
庆祝我可爱的小梅薇思的又一个生日
Another birthday for my sweet little Mavis,
同样也庆祝躲避人类的又一个成功之年！
and another successful year of refuge from them!
这些是我们的督查拍到的…
These are recent human images
…人类最新的照片
our surveillance has uncovered.
为了压倒我们，人类变得更肥了
They are getting fatter so as to overpower us.
而且他们越穿越少
And they are wearing less clothing,
以便于在勒死我们或者撬开我们脑袋…
allowing more movement to strangle us
…往里放糖果时更利索
or cut open our heads and put candy in them.
但他们永远…
But they will never
…找不到我们这里
find us here.
可恶的混蛋，你们永远赢不了！
Evil villain, you will never win!
好了诸位，派对39分钟后开始
Okie doke. The fun starts in 30 minutes.
现在我得去看看我的小女儿
Right now, I have to see my little girl.
她可不再是小孩子了！
She's not so little any more!
不，她是！
Yes, she is!
外面吵吵什么呢？
What's going on out there?
我们到旅社了吗？
Are we at the hotel?
弗兰克，你给没给我们预定个双人按摩？
Frank, did you book us for a tandem massage?
在卡西莫多的餐厅订位了没有？
Did you get us a table at Hunchback's?
你到底有没有在办事？
Did you do anything?
不客气
You're welcome.
怎么回事？
What's going on?
爸爸，你说过
Dad, you said that
我118岁的时候，就可以去外面的世界
when I turned 118, I could go out into the world
就跟那些在旅社中来来去去的大人一样
like every other adult that gets to come and go from this hotel.
“可是梅薇小宝，那不安全，吧啦吧啦”
"But, Mavey Wavey, it's not safe. Bleh, bleh-bleh."
爸爸，30年前，你答应我的
Dad, 30 years ago, you promised.
我记得我们都吃着老鼠…
I remember, we were both eating mice,
…然后你明确地告诉我你会信守承诺
and you specifically said that you gave me your word.
请勿打扰
Do not disturb.
- 请勿打扰 - 请勿打扰
Do not disturb. Do not disturb.
请勿打扰
Do not disturb.
- 请勿打扰 - 请勿打扰
Do not disturb. Do not disturb.
- 请勿打扰 - 早上好，阁下
Do not disturb. Good morning, Your Eminence.
阿姨，把这个房间打扫干净！
Maid, clean up this room!
是你啊，希望你能信守诺言
It's you. Glad you could make it.
- 她起来了吗？ - 起来了
Is she up yet? Oh, she's up.
她已经准备要走了，我说“走” 是指出去看看外面的世界
She's ready to go. And by "go," I mean go. As in, go check the world out.
你要怎么办？怎么跟她说？
What you gonna do? What you gonna say?
我都安排好了，拜托，放松点 干好你自己的工作
I got it covered. Please, relax. Just do your job.
早上好，梅薇小宝！
Good morning, Mavey Wavey!
生日快乐，我的小心肝儿！
Happy birthday, my little mouse!
谢谢，爸爸
Thank you, Dad.
我知道今天是我的生日
I know it's my birthday.
我安排了好多有趣的节目
I have so much fun planned. Whoo-hoo!
但首先，我们要一起抓些蝎子
But first, we go catch some scorpions together,
就我们俩哟?
just the two of us, yes, dead-ums?
爸爸，拜托，听我说
Dad, please, let me speak.
有件事我们得谈谈
There's something we have to talk about.
你想去外面的世界看看，行
You want to go out into the world. You can.
啊哈！
Aha!
我就知道你会这么说
I knew you were gonna say that.
但是爸爸，你承诺过的
But, Dad, you gave me your word,
你也知道，我知道德古拉的承诺多神圣 （相传德古拉伯爵是世上第一个吸血鬼）
and you know that I know that a Dracula's word is sacred.
彼此的信任是我们之间…
That our trust is the core of our...
等等，什么？
Wait, what?
我说行
I said you can go.
你在哄我吧
You're just playing with me.
不不不，你到了可以驾驶灵车的年纪了
No, no, no, no. You're old enough to drive a hearse now,
你长大了，可以自己做选择
you're old enough to make your own choices.
你可以去
You can go.
太好了！太好了！
Holy rabies! Holy rabies!
哇，哇，站住
Whoa, whoa. Stop.
稍等，小宝
Wait a second, sweetfangs.
你这是要去哪儿？
Where are you going?
哦，好吧，我要去天堂
Oh, well, I'm going to paradise,
这些是我认为需要的行李
and this is just some stuff that I thought I would need.
- 天堂？ - 是啊，你知道的
Paradise? Yeah, you know.
你跟妈妈就是在那儿邂逅的
It's that place out there where you and Mom met.
天堂 夏威夷应有尽有
旺达阿姨说…
Auntie Wanda says you two
…你俩几乎是，一见钟情！
were just like, Zing!
我不知道什么“一见钟情”
I don't know from "Zing."
你从哪儿找到这张卡片的？
Where did you find that card?
你抽屉里
In one of your drawers.
为什么你从来不给我讲你们的邂逅？
Why won't you ever tell me about how you met?
那其实是夏威夷
It's actually Hawaii.
夏什么？
Ha-what-what?
听着，亲爱的，我知道你很兴奋
Look, honey, I know you're excited,
但大家长途跋涉地来给你庆祝生日
but everyone has gone to great lengths to come see you on your birthday.
我知道，他们一向如此
I know. They always do.
但是，这种聚会对我来说是否有点太小儿科了？
But aren't I getting a little old for these parties?
我喜欢他们，但我真的想看见点新意
I love them, but I really want to see new things.
或许是某个跟我年龄相仿的朋友
Maybe meet somebody my age.
好啦，别别，别哭
Come on. No, no, don't do that.
别让我看见你那撅着嘴的小脸儿
Don't give me the pouty batface.
好吧，墓地再过去一段儿距离…
Okay, there is a human village
…有个人类的村子
just a little ways past the cemetery.
你可以到那儿看看，30分钟左右回来
You could go there and be back in, like, 30 minutes or so.
第一次不能出去太久
It should be plenty for your first time.
好吧，虽然不是夏威威，但我想…
Well, it's not Ha-wee-wee, but I guess
…应该也不错
it's still technically out there.
好好好！
Okay, okay, okay!
谢谢你信任我
Thanks for trusting me.
当然，小家伙
Of course, my little one.
我跟你承诺过的
I gave you my word.
嘿，亲爱的
Hey, honey!
- 快看看！ - 大家好
Look at this! Hey, guys.
你在为明天而兴奋了吧？
You excited about tomorrow?
没有此时此刻兴奋
Not as excited as I am right now.
你们肯定不会相信，但是爸爸…
You're not gonna believe this, but Dad is letting me
…允许我自己去看看人类的村子了！
go out on my own to see a human village!
- 什么？ - 不！
What? No!
抱歉，德古！
Excuse me. Drac!
你疯了吗？
Have you lost it?
让你的宝贝女儿去那个…
Letting your own daughter out there
…充满恐怖人类的地方？你常警告我们的
with those horrible humans you always tell us about?
你建这个城堡是为了什么！
That's why you built this place.
他们恨我们，他们很恶毒
They hate us. They're vicious.
而且吵得要命！
And they're very loud!
尤妮丝阿姨，没准他们已经变了
Auntie Eunice, maybe they've changed.
我就去街上看看他们变成什么样
I'm just gonna fly down the street and see how it goes.
好吧亲爱的，注意安全
Okay, honey, be safe.
穿暖和点，带把剑
Bring warm clothes and a sword.
小心铁叉
And look out for pitchforks.
也别让任何人挖你的脑子
Don't you let anyone scoop your brains out, either.
最好待在阴暗处
Maybe stay in the shadows.
躲在房檐下偷偷观察比较好玩
It's more fun to just observe from under a house.
伙计们，伙计们，她能行
Guys, guys. She can handle it.
她可是德古拉
She's a Dracula, for Pete's sake.
不过说真的，小心火
But seriously, watch out for fire.
火很厉害
Fire bad.
再见了，各位
Bye, everyone.
Whoo-hoo!
德古，真不敢相信你居然这么淡定地让她走了
Drac, I can't believe how calm you are about her leaving.
我真为你骄傲
I'm proud of you.
德古？德古？
Drac? Drac?
德古去哪儿了？
Where did Drac go?
Whoo-hoo!
太棒了！
This is awesome!
这儿是墓地，跟爸爸说得一样
There's the cemetery, just like Dad said.
Whoo-hoo!
有人吗？
Uh... Hello?
那儿有人吗？
Anybody out there?
吸血鬼，咬脚趾！
Vampire. Bite toes!
Oh!
嗨，人类
Hi, humans.
没事儿吧？我叫梅薇思·德古拉，我…
Everything okay? My name is Mavis Dracula, and I...
吸血鬼
Vampire.
- 烧衣服 - 烧我的衣服？
- Burn clothes. - Burn my clothes?
- 真的吗？嗯… - 吸血鬼！
Really? Um... Vampire!
- 把糖果交出来 - 糖果！
We take your candy. Candy!
我没有恶意，真的
I'm friendly. I really am.
- 冷静点 - 糖果
Calm down, now. Candy.
我只想打个招呼
I just wanted to say hi.
拜托，我没伤害任何人
Please. I've never hurt anyone.
我念的私塾
I'm homeschooled.
那是大蒜吗？
Is that garlic?
天呐，你们着火了
Holy rabies, you're on fire.
我能做点什么吗？有什么需要帮忙的？
Can I do anything? Can I help you?
爸爸说得没错
Dad was right.
奏效了
It worked.
这下我的宝贝永远安全了
Now my baby will be safe forever.
好了，各位，都回去工作吧
All right, everybody, get back to work now.
嘿，你不需要服装模特
Hey. You don't need a mannequin.
把它放下，快点
Leave the mannequin here. Come on.
你去哪儿了？
Where you been?
干嘛鬼鬼祟祟的？
Why you sneaking around?
安静点
Shh. Quiet.
小宝，你这么快就回来了？
Sweetheart, have you returned so soon?
请进，爸爸
Oh. Come in, Dad.
怎么样？那个世界好玩吗？
How'd it go? How was the big world?
外面什么样子？
How was it out there?
还行，爸爸
It was okay, Dad.
什么？怎么了？
What? What's the matter?
爸爸，你是对的
Dad, you were right.
人类很可怕
Humans are awful.
你说得都对
They were everything you said.
- 他们想要咬我的脚趾 - 你的脚趾？
They wanted to bite my toes. Your toes?
他们还在面包上涂大蒜
And they had garlic on bread.
什么？看着我
What? Look at me.
我鸡皮疙瘩都起来了，我好害怕
I'm getting goose bumps, I'm so scared.
真抱歉，小宝
I'm so sorry, sweetheart.
让你看到这些我很难过
I hate that you had to see that.
真抱歉我居然怀疑你
I'm so sorry I doubted you.
我再也不会离开这儿了
I'll never leave here again.
好，好
Okay. Okay.
听着，爸爸要给你办一个史上最好的生日派对
Look, Daddy's going to make you the bestest birthday ever.
看我给你带什么来了
Look what I brought you.
你的小虫蛋糕
Your wormcakes.
别难过了
Don't be sad any more.
记着吗，今年可以拆开妈妈给你的礼物了
Remember, this is the year we open Mommy's present for you.
她给我送了什么礼物？
What did she get me?
我们看看就知道了
We'll see.
她说你不到118岁就不能拆
She said never to open until you're 118.
我们等了这么久
We've waited this long.
你先吃小虫蛋糕
You eat your wormcakes.
准备好了就下楼，宝贝
You come down whenever you're ready, honey.
Phew. Ooh.
你做了什么？
What did you do?
做我该做的
What I had to.
Mm-hmm.
有一天她会感谢我的
She'll thank me one day.
对，把我头弄小那个家伙也这么说
Yeah, that's what the guy who shrunk my head said.
Ahh.
想要啥，饼干？
Yes, what do you want, a cookie?
你做得对，老兄
You did all right, man.
快干活
Move on already.
Phew!
Yeah.
吸血鬼！吸血鬼！
Vampire! Vampire!
人
A human.
你是谁？你怎么找到这儿的？
Who are you? And how did you find this place?
哦，我叫约翰森
Oh, I'm Jonathan.
我跟一些家伙们一块儿登山…
And I was just mountain climbing with some dudes...
…然后听说了这个幽灵森林的故事
...and heard this story about a spooky forest.
谁不想见识一下幽灵森林呢，对吧？
And who's not going to go into a spooky forest, right?
于是，我又看到了那些笨手笨脚的东西着了火
So, then I see these goofy-looking dudes on fire-
就一路尾随他们来到这个，惊人的城堡
And I just kind of followed them to this, like, amazing castle.
但是，当然，聪明起见
But, of course, be smart.
没有营火，也没有烽火台
No bonfires, no firework shows.
- 你们有多少人？ - 就我一个
How many of you are there? Just me.
我喜欢独自旅行
I like to hit it alone.
在青年旅社你能遇到很多厉害的人
You meet so many awesome people in the youth hostels.
嘿，说到“厉害”，你的披肩超拉风的
Hey, speaking of awesome, that cape thing is killing it.
这儿是有化妆舞会之类的吗？
Is there, like, a costume party here?
我干了些什么？
What have I done?
都是我的错
This is all my fault.
你得离开
You have to leave.
- 哦不 - 打扰了
- Oh, no. - Excuse me.
你湖里的一只食人鱼太粗野了
One of your piranhas in the lake is very rude.
他吃了我嫂子
He ate my sister-in-law.
马上回来
Be right with you.
德古拉先生，我们订的是池景房间
Mr. Dracula, we asked for a room with a view of the pool.
房间没问题，我们想预约按摩
The room's fine. We want to book a massage.
- 对，瑞典式按摩 - 指压按摩
Yes, Swedish. Shiatsu.
- 香薰按摩 - 背部按摩
Aromatherapy. Lower back.
- 你们提供热石吗？ - 我们要按摩
Do you have hot-stone? We want a massage.
- 我回头跟你讲，六头先生 - 希望如此
I'll get back to you, Mr. Hydraberg. I hope so.
- 我不相信 - 但愿你真会回来
I doubt it. See that you do.
- 是六头女士 - 谢谢
That's Ms. Hydraberg. Thanks.
- 认识你很高兴 - [乔纳森]：伙计，说真的，怎么回事？
Yes, nice to see you. JONATHAN: Dude, seriously, what's up?
我在这儿快要窒息了
It's kind of funky to breathe under here.
德古，嘿，德古，梅薇思怎么样了？
Drac. Hey, Drac. How'd it go with Mavey?
嘿，你跑哪儿去了？
Hey. Where'd you go?
Wow!
这房间对于一个宏伟的城堡来讲小了点儿啊
This room's kind of small for a big castle.
没有床，但这些簸箕可挺酷
No bed, but check out these awesome dustpans they give you.
闭嘴，你个蠢货
Quiet, you fool.
你这玩意里装了什么武器？
What weapons are you keeping in this container?
铁叉吗？
Your pitchforks?
Oh!
我无法呼吸了
I can't breathe.
熏死我了
It's killing me.
是啊，的确应该抖一抖折起来了
Yeah, definitely due for a fluff and fold.
这是什么？
What is this?
酷刑工具？
A torture device?
秘密精神控制器？
A secret mind controller?
你读不出我的想法的
You won't read my thoughts.
我不会让你得逞的
I won't let you.
老兄，那不过是音乐而已
Dude, it's just music.
来，听听看
Here, try it.
Ohh!
我的灵魂都要被夺走了！
It's taking my soul!
什么？这首很赞诶，别落伍了
What? It's a good jam. Don't be a grandpa.
你得离开
You need to go.
从来没有人类进入过这个城堡，要是被看见…
No human has ever entered this castle. And if someone should see you,
…旅社的安全性就无法保障了 大家就再也不会来了
the safety of the hotel, the sanctuary, no one would ever come again.
试试看
Yeah, go for it.
“再也不会来了”
"Ever come again!"
我喜欢你冷酷性感的声音，太夸张了
I love your Dracula voice. It's so over the top.
要是梅薇思看到了你，她就会知道我撒了谎，不！
And Mavis, if she saw you, she would know that I lied. No!
梅薇思是谁？这是她的房间吗？
Who's Mavis? Is this her room?
我一向跟室友处得很来
I'm good with a roommate.
我有六个兄弟一块长大，所以很懂得分享
I had six brothers growing up, sol could totally share.
我不能杀他
I can't kill him.
这会让怪物文明倒退几百年
It would set monsters back hundreds of years.
有一次，我在汉堡的时候…
One time, in Hamburg, I roomed with this dude
抓到一个室友偷我的洗发水
who I caught stealing my shampoo.
我说“哇，老兄” 他就朝我砸花盆，不过他人挺酷的
I said, "Whoa, man," and he threw a flower pot at me, but he was cool.
你嘟囔什么呢？
What are you babbling about?
什么？哇
What? Whoa.
快看看这些戏服，帅啊
Check out these awesome costumes.
戏服
Costumes.
干嘛？抱歉老兄，你不能抢走我的包
What's this? Sorry, man. I just can't be without my backpack.
- 要知道，我全部家当都在里面了 - 就放在这儿
You know, everything I own's in there. It'll be right here.
好吧，只是，我很爱我的背包
Okay, I just... I love my backpack.
哇，嘿，你在干嘛？
Whoa. Hey, what are you doing?
你…你对我的头发做了什么？
What are you... What are you doing to my hair?
住手，等等，痒死了
Stop. Oh, wait, that tickles.
得了，伙计
Come on, man.
看看吧，我是科学小怪
Check it out. I'm a Franken-homie.
- 对，哈喽 - 看看我啊！
Yes, hello. Look at me!
一切都很正常，这儿没什么问题 他只是跟着我的一个小怪
This is totally normal, not a problem here. This is just a monster with me.
大家今晚都要玩得开心啊
Man, everybody stepped it up tonight.
等等，为什么往前门走？我们要走了吗？
Wait, why are we going to the front door? Are we leaving?
你好，德古拉！
Bonjour, Dracula!
嘿，长鼻王，近来可好？
Hey, Sniffy. What's going on?
不是现在，卡西莫多
Not right now, Quasimodo.
什么？
What?
不，别说傻话
No. Don't be absurd.
那不是人，是德古拉先生
It's not a human, but Monsieur Dracula.
多搞笑，是我啊
How ridiculous. It's me.
<i>先生<i/>
Monsieur.
- 芥末蜥蜴脚 - 芥末蜥蜴脚？
The devilled lizard fingers. Devilled lizard fingers?
我要的是肝脏卷
I asked for spleens-in-blankets.
你这蠢货！我告诉你的
You ugly fool! I told you, he doesn't like
- 他不喜欢蜥蜴脚 - 可你说…
the lizard fingers! But you said...
哇，看看那套戏服
Whoa. Check that costume out.
说真的，我得问问你，要怎么才能脱掉这身衣服啊？
Wow. Seriously, I just have to ask you: How are you pulling this off?
看起来跟真的一样
I mean, it looks so real.
就好像，我能把手插过去…
Like, I could just put my hand right through...
你要干嘛？
What do you think you're doing?
是真的，你们是真骷髅！
She's real. You're real!
对，我还会暴打你一顿，别碰我老婆！
Yeah, and I'll give you a real beating. Keep your hands out of my wife!
哦，不
Oh, no.
Ay-yi-yi-yi!
宝贝，我刚还不知道你去哪了呢
Honey, I just didn't know where you were.
我们都以为你还在外面呢
We thought you were still out.
不，真不知道我以前怎么会想要出去
Oh, no. I don't know why I ever wanted to leave.
人类太讨厌了
The humans are so boring.
梅薇思，宝贝，你还好吗？
Mavis, honey, are you all right?
还好，太奇怪了
Yeah, I think so. That was weird.
我头好疼
My head hurts.
- 呃，那是谁？ - 什么那是谁？
Um, who is that? Who is what?
哦，他啊
Oh, that.
不是谁
That is nobody.
- 真的吗，爸爸？ - “爸爸”？
Seriously, Dad? "Dad"?
是啊，我就知道，德古拉的女儿 每个人一开始都害怕
Yeah, I know, Dracula's daughter. Everyone freaks out at first.
德古拉？
Dracula?
好了，我们得走了
Okay, we got to go.
求你别杀我，我还年轻
Please don't kill me. I'm so young.
还有很多地方想去
I have so many places I want to see.
我还买了大卫马修斯乐队演唱会的门票呢
I've got tickets to six Dave Matthews Band concerts.
我得活着出去
I'm getting out of here.
给我闭嘴
Shut up already.
你吵吵嚷嚷的让我没法思考
It's impossible for me to think with all your noise.
抱歉，格伦，继续睡吧
Sorry, Glen. Go back to sleep.
- 等等，你要吸我的血吗？ - 标准的人类偏见
Wait. Aren't you going to suck my blood? Classic human paranoia.
人类的血太肥腻了，你也不知道血的来源
Human blood is so fatty, and you never know where it's been.
那么，德古拉不吸血吗？
So, Dracula doesn't drink blood?
不，我喝人造血
No, I use a blood substitute.
不管是近似血还是搅拌血 喝起来都跟真的一样
Either Near Blood or Blood Beaters. You can't tell the difference.
也就是说，你真是德古拉伯爵
So, wow, you're, like, the real Count Dracula.
“我是德古拉，吧啦吧啦”
Like, "I'm Dracula. Bleh, bleh-bleh."
我这辈子没说过那玩意，“吧啦吧啦吧啦”
I've never said that in my life. "Bleh, bleh-bleh."
我不知道从哪儿传出去的
I don't know where that comes from.
我能问一句，这到底是什么地方吗？
Can I just ask, what exactly is this place?
这是什么地方？
What is this place?
这是我给那些怪物们建造的城堡
It's a place I built for all those monsters out there,
藏在阴暗里，躲避人类迫害
lurking in the shadows, hiding from the persecution of humankind.
一个让他们可以带着全家人来放松的地方
A place for them and their families to come to and be themselves.
一个没有火把，没有铁叉，没有暴民的地方
A place void of torches, pitchforks, angry mobs.
一个安宁，放松
A place of peace, relaxation
平静的地方
and tranquility.
太帅了，也就是说，这是怪物的旅社？
Cool. So, it's like a hotel for monsters?
对，可以这么说
Yes, exactly. "A hotel for monsters." Way to sum it up.
好了，骑到我背上，我们得走了
Okay, hop on my back. We're leaving.
天呐，你变成蝙蝠了
Oh, man, you're a bat now.
我总是想飞，那感觉怎么样？
I always wanted to fly. What's it like?
太疯狂了，等等，等等，我想留下来
This is insane. Wait. Wait, I want to stay.
能让科学怪人在我衣服上签个名吗？ 再让我见见隐形人？
Can Frankenstein sign my costume? Can I meet the Invisible Man?
嘿，要是我把手塞到隐形人嘴里…
Hey, if I stuck my hand in the Invisible Man's mouth,
- …他会消失吗？ - 嗨
- would it disappear? - Hi.
梅薇！你在干嘛，我的小宝贝？
Mavey! What are you doing, my sweet little blood orange?
我们的朋友要走了
Our friend was just leaving.
对，他要抓着我飞出窗子
Yeah, he was flying me out the window.
这家伙啊，他太好玩了
This guy, he's so funny.
看看，你脸上有东西
Look, you have something on your face.
好好配合我演戏，否则别想拿回你那宝贝背包
Play along if you ever want to see your precious backpack.
哇，你刚刚变成蝙蝠的时候是不是没穿衣服？
Whoa. So, wait, you didn't have any clothes on when you were a bat?
还是它们也变成了蝙蝠大小？
Or were they bat-sized?
他到底是谁？
Who exactly is that?
宝贝
Hmm. Honeybat.
你看，今天是你的生日
You see, it's your birthday.
我想给你办一场此生最好最特别的生日会
And you know I want you to have the bestest, specialest party of your life.
所以，我需要个帮手
So, well, I needed some help.
你需要帮手？
You needed help?
呃，对，我很厉害
Well, look, I am very good, but I thought it would be
但我想要是有个 跟你年龄相仿的家伙协助策划会更好
even more bestest, specialest if someone closer to your age helped plan the party.
- 你跟我年龄相仿？ - 当然
You're my age? Sure.
呃，你多大了？
Well, how old are you?
118岁
118.
一百…
One hundred and...
对，我121岁了
Yeah, I'm 121.
- 真的？ - 嗯
Really? Mm-hmm.
看到了？一切都非常非常正常
You see? Everything is very, very normal.
我在举办舞会，他帮忙
I'm throwing a party, and he's helping.
- 先生，有紧急情况 - 现在没空
Sir, there's an emergency. Not now.
没看见我们正在讨论一件很正常的事儿吗？
Can't you see we're in the middle of something very normal here?
等等，怎么回事？
Wait, what's going on here?
你的宝贝旅社出了紧急状况，你却不急着解决？
There's an emergency in your precious hotel, and you're not running to fix it?
为什么？因为他吗？
Why? Is it because of him?
哇，看着我的脸
Whoa, look at my face.
不，宝贝，当然不是
No, precious bones, it's not because of him.
很好，那就赶紧去处理紧急情况，我来陪他
Good. Then go check on the emergency, and I'll keep him company.
- 不！绝对不行 - 什么？
No! Anything but that! What?
我是说，他得去做策划呢
I mean, because he needs time to plan.
要是你陪着他，他就没法策划了
And if you're keeping him company, then he's not planning.
要是有人陪着…
He is company-keeping,
…策划，策划就做不出来了
and then the plan, it's... it doesn't get planned.
- 编得不错 - 闭嘴！
Mm-hmm. Good one. Shut up!
好的，要是你一会儿不策划了，我们可以去散散步
Okay. So, maybe if you're not planning later, we can hang out.
- 听起来不错 - 听到了吗？
Sounds good. Yes. You hear that?
听起来不错
It sounds good.
你们会去散步的，一会儿见，宝贝
So you will hang out. See you later, my honey. Lovely.
好了，你不能去散步了
Okay, you're not hanging out.
因为你得走了
Because you are leaving.
你刚才不是这么说的
But the opposite, you said.
可是大人，紧急情况怎么办
But, sir, the emergency.
跟上我
Follow me.
那小子真臭
Boy, that kid smelt.
我们这是要去哪儿
Where are we going?
从密道把你送走
Just getting rid of you
这样她就看不见我们了
through a secret tunnel so she does not see us.
我能问个问题吗？
So, can I ask you a question?
你们真的怕大蒜吗？
Is that real, about the garlic thing?
对，我不能吃，嗓子会肿
Yes, I cannot have it. My throat swells.
那…用木杆刺穿你们的心你们会死吗？
Huh. Wooden stake to the heart?
当然，刺穿心脏谁不死啊？
Yeah, well, who wouldn't that kill?
就是这儿了
Ah. Here we go.
抱歉，我有点儿迷路
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm a little lost.
是，我知道你在度蜜月，抱歉
Yes, I know it's your honeymoon. I apologize.
你们继续
Go back to doing what you were doing.
我不常来地道
I'm not down here much.
这是人类入侵时的紧急出口
It's meant to be an exit if humans ever invade.
那么，我应该是第一个来这儿的人？太酷了
So, I'm, like, the first human here, huh? That's really cool.
总算找到了
Oh, boy.
我想这下没错了
I think this is it.
- 出什么事儿了？ - 非常抱歉
What's happening? I'm terribly sorry.
- 是我的错 - 你们这些人什么毛病？
My mistake. What is wrong with you people?
老兄，这地方太棒了
Oh, man. This place is amazing.
拜托，让我耳根清净一会儿
Okay, I could really use some silence right now.
好吧，事不过三…
All right, third time's a...
德古
Drac.
弗兰基？
Yes, Frankie?
嘿，伙计，你在干嘛？
Hey, buddy, what you been doing?
别动
Don't move.
- 别提了 - 你在干嘛？
Never mind that. What you been doing?
我们想排练一下派对上的演出
We wanted to practice our big number for Mavis's party,
但这些小崽子一直占着舞台
and then these losers wouldn't get off the bandstand.
好了，把僵尸莫扎特放下
Okay. Put down Zombie Mozart,
还有巴赫和贝多芬，快点
Bach and Beethoven this instant.
你还用排练吗，僵尸贝多芬？
Did you get to rehearse at all, Zombie Beethoven?
（僵尸哼的是贝多芬《命运交响曲》）
听着，德古，我们想像原来那样演支曲子
Listen, Drac, we wanted to play something, like old times.
还希望你能加入进来
We even thought maybe you'd sing with us.
算了吧，老弟 你知道玛莎出事后我就不当众唱歌了
Come on, fellas. You know that I haven't sung in public since Martha.
是，但我们想要是你能加入梅薇思会多开心啊
Yeah, but we just thought how much, you know, Mavis would love it.
我说不！
I said no!
别再跟我提这个！
Don't ask me again!
好了，现在跟僵尸们抱抱，大家言归于好
Okay. Now, let's hug the zombies. Let's all make up.
- 他吓到你们了吧 - 我才没被吓到
Wow. He really scared you. I wasn't scared.
我只是出于礼貌，知道吗？
I was being polite, okay?
嘿，你在这儿干嘛呢？我还以为你在策划
Hey. What are you doing here? I thought you were planning.
我还不知道你叫什么名字
I never caught your name.
我叫梅薇思
My name's Mavis.
梅薇思？真好听
Mavis? That's a pretty neat name.
是啊，我妈妈取的
Yeah, my mom picked it.
那么，能告诉我你叫什么吗？
So, are you going to tell me your name?
我？我的名字？问得好
Me? My name? Good question.
好吧，很显然，我叫弗兰肯斯坦
Well, obviously, I'm Frankenstein.
不，你不是，弗兰肯斯坦是我叔叔，他在那儿
No, you're not. Frankenstein is my uncle over there.
跟僵尸莫扎特拥抱那个
The gentleman hugging Zombie Mozart.
是，当然，他是你叔叔
Right. Of course, he's your uncle.
好吧，我不是那个弗兰肯斯坦
Well, see, I'm not "the" Frankenstein.
我是他堂弟，约翰斯坦
I'm his cousin, Johnnystein.
- 约翰斯坦？ - 嘿，梅薇思
Johnnystein? Hey, Mavis.
那是谁？
Who is that?
这些怪物会杀了我吗？
Are these monsters going to kill me?
只要他们认为你也是怪物就不会
Not as long as they think you're a monster.
这有点种族歧视
Huh? That's kind of racist.
我们一会儿再谈
We'll talk later.
- 他在拿我开涮吗？ - 不，没有
Is he making fun of me? No, no.
他当然没有，因为他是…
Of course he's not, because he's...
他是你堂弟，约翰斯坦
He's your cousin, Johnnystein.
对对对
Yes, yes, yes.
我没有堂弟
I don't have no cousin.
不不，你有，他是你六弟，远亲
No, no, you do. He's your sixth cousin, three times removed.
跟你的右手有点血缘关系
On your right arm's side.
你有堂弟？
You have a cousin?
弗兰克，要是你的手臂会说话…
Frank, if your arm could talk,
…它就会告诉你它的原主人有个弟弟
he would tell you that the original owner of your arm had a brother.
还娶了个老婆
Who married a woman.
- 他… - 杀死了一头猪
Who was... For strangling a pig.
我胳膊里流着杀猪人的血？
I have pig-strangling blood in my arm?
那可挺酷的
That's kind of cool.
好吧，堂弟，很高兴认识你
Well, cuz, great to meet you.
你是来干什么的，约翰？
So, what brings you here, Johnny?
- 那是什么？ - 抱歉
Wah! What was that? Oh, sorry.
说话前我应该先清清嗓子的
I should really clear my throat before I speak.
不过，你是来干嘛的？
Anyway, what brings you here?
呃…
Oh. Uh.
派对策划
Party planner.
对，我请斯坦先生来帮我策划梅薇思的生日派对
Yes, I have recruited Mr. Stein here to help me with Mavis's birthday party.
等等，你请人来帮你？
Wait a minute, you asked someone to help you?
你这个控制狂船长？
Captain Control Freak?
是伯爵…
It's Count...
对，他们都是年轻人，我觉得他的意见会很有用
And yes, I thought having a Mavis contemporary would be useful.
他的确需要点新鲜点子
Yeah, he totally needed a fresher perspective.
好吧，约翰，那几位僵尸先生…
Okay, Johnny, Mr. Tight Coffin over here
…打算让那些老东西上场
was planning to have these powdered lame-os play at the party.
所以，我觉得我们得让气氛嗨起来
So, anyways, we thought we could liven things up a bit.
哇！你们都要表演？露两手看看！
Whoa! You all play? Let's check you guys out!
# 姑娘 #
# 不敢相信这是你的狂欢之夜 #
# 仿佛就在昨天你还吃着蚊子 #
# 而现在却已经吃青蛙老鼠了 #
# 把它们像立体脆一样吞掉 #
# 告诉我 #
# 时光都溜去了何处，宝贝 #
喔喔喔，打住，伙计们
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Hold on, guys.
打住
Stop.
这很棒，不过有点儿过时
That's cute, but kind of old school.
是啊，谢了，约翰
Yes, thank you, Johnny.
你们需要点有节奏的音乐
You got to totally tempo things up.
来，我来给你们示范一下
Here, let me show you.
狼人，给我个调！
Werewolf man, give me a jam!
二、三、四！
Two, three, four!
# 牙齿尖尖的吸血鬼女孩 #
# 发型乖乖的超可爱 #
# 小公主就要变女王 #
# 蝙蝠女神今天就要118岁 #
- 118！ - 说118！
118! Say 118!
118！
118!
耶！跳下去咯！
Yeah! Stage dive!
太棒了
Awesome.
我太激动了
I am so blown away right now.
我想我堂弟会把这个派对…
I think my cuz is gonna make this
…办成史上最精彩的一次！
the best party ever!
是啊！说不定他能想法子给我找些小妞来
Yeah! Maybe he can find a way to get me some chicks.
我们应该办个舞蹈比赛！
We should do a dance contest!
绝对不行
We're not doing any of that.
我们得按着节目单来，知道吗？
We've got to stay on schedule, all right?
知道了，爸爸，知道了
All right, Dad, all right.
- 约翰，你也要来哦 - 我不确定…
Johnny, you're coming, too. I don't know.
- 跟德古拉一起很棒的 - 约翰，一起来吧
Is it cool with Dracula? Johnny, come with us.
N-27
N-27.
G-61
G-61.
找到了！找到了！
Bingo! Bingo!
好大的胆子
How dare you.
知道是什么博士造的我吗？ （弗兰肯斯坦博士）
Do you know what doctor made me?
我什么也没做
I didn't do that.
圆圈？
Circles?
苍蝇？
Fly?
- 手？ - 胶卷？
Hands? Film.
- 呕吐 - 呕吐？
Vomit. The Vomit?
- 吐了 - 不，刚才那不是提示
The Throw Up. No. That wasn't a clue.
什么也不是？
Nothing?
- 空虚？ - 眼镜？
Emptiness? Glasses?
- 眼镜？ - 摇摇晃晃的眼镜？
Glasses? Glasses shaking?
向一边倾斜的眼镜？
Glasses shaking sideways!
镜中奇缘？
Through The Looking-Glass?
我玩不好这个
I stink at this.
我什么也没干
I didn't do that.
拉回来，向上，推
And pull it back. And up. And push.
转身，回来
And twist. And back.
向上，转身
And up. And twist.
推
And push.
不，这个不用学
No. Don't copy that.
向后，向上，转身
And back. And up. And twist.
给我一份麋鹿鼻子蛋卷
Let me get a bubonic moose nose omelet
配上蟑螂糊和老鼠酱
with cockroach paste and mouse jelly.
再来点蛋白
And with egg whites.
你好，德古拉先生
Bonjour, Monsieur Dracula!
要我为您煎蛋卷吗？
May I make you an omelet?
不不不，我不饿
No, no, no, no. I'm not hungry.
什么？艾丝美拉达，你又闻到了？
What? Esmeralda, you smell it again?
- 人？ - 我饿了
Human? I am hungry.
约翰，你去过泰姬陵？
Johnny, you've been to the Taj Mahal?
得了吧，没有哪个怪物去过泰姬陵
Come on. No monster's been to the Taj.
真希望我能去那儿
Man, I wish I could go there.
听着，我要50个蛋卷
You know what? I'll take 50 omelets.
听见了吗！赶紧做！
You heard the man! Make them!
你怎么对付那些暴民？
How did you deal with the mobs?
是啊，夏天的确特疯狂
Yeah, it does get pretty crazy in the summer.
不过，随机应变就好了
But, you know, you just got to roll.
他说随机应变，太酷了他能随机应变
He just rolls. That's cool that he rolls.
是啊是啊，很酷
Yes, yes, cool.
看，宝贝，我给你拿了百吉饼 涂着你最爱的尖叫奶酪
Look, love droppings, I brought you a bagel with your favorite, scream cheese.
太棒了，谢谢爸爸
Holy rabies. Thanks, Dad.
约翰，尝尝尖叫奶酪吧，可好吃了
Johnny, try some scream cheese, it's awesome.
不错
Oh, cool.
不过我对这东西过敏，好意心领了
But I'm scream cheese intolerant. So, polite pass.
对，你过敏
Yes, of course you are.
约翰，我们能聊聊派对策划的事儿吗？
Johnny, can we party-plan talk for a minute?
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
要是他们发现你是人，你就完蛋了！
If they find out you are human, they'll go bat poop!
别紧张，没人怀疑
Relax. No one suspects anything.
唯一不正常的就是你老鬼鬼祟祟地找我说话
The only thing that looks weird is how much whispering you're doing.
赶紧的，告诉他们你要去游泳，显得兴奋点
Just wrap it up. You will say you are going in the pool and act excited.
然后说你背疼，要先走一步
And then you will say you hurt your back and you have to leave.
刺激的来咯！
Here come good times! Whoo!
喂，老兄，哦，我的背
Oh, dudes. Oh, my back.
我在你背上！
I'm on your back!
不不，他是说“我背疼”
No, no. He said, "Oh, my back."
- 骑到我背上来 - 我们也这么玩
Get on my back! Let's do it.
来吧，水上搏斗，推倒他们！
Aw, here we go. Chicken fight! Push them off!
水上搏斗！
Chicken fight!
我们来咯，约翰
We got you, Johnny.
你完蛋了
You're going down. Whoa.
咱走着瞧，“梅薇小宝”
Oh, yeah, we'll see, "Mavey Wavey."
冷静冷静！
Okay, calm down with the fight chickens!
各位，别闹了！
Everyone, stop the roughhousing!
Whoo!
弗兰克，别伤到自己…
Frank, if you hurt yourself...
知道了，亲爱的
I got it, honey.
我们斯坦家族的男人就是为此而生的
The Stein boys are bred for this kind of thing.
杰罗尼莫！ （美国空军跳伞时的口号）
Geronimo!
Eh-heh-heh.
孩子们，你们怎么能这么做？
Kids, Why'd you do that?
我刚去游了泳
I was just in the pool.
水很凉
The water's cold.
少管我！
Don't judge me!
约翰，你的妆
Johnny. Your makeup.
你的妆！
Your makeup!
上来，快
Climb out. Now.
天呐
Oh, man.
我猜伯爵大人是想游游泳
I guess the Count wanted to go for a swim.
炮弹发射！
Cannonball!
你搞砸了，小鬼，你彻底搞砸了
Oh, you messed up, baby. You messed up big-time.
我告诉你要低调点
I told you to take it down.
要是被发现，你会毁了我的旅社的
You'll ruin my hotel if they find out.
好吧，可能你只是嫉妒…
Well, maybe you're just jealous
…大家在这儿玩得很有乐趣
that people are finally having fun at this place.
乐趣？那可不是乐趣
Oh, that? That was not fun.
大家毫无秩序地乱跑乱跳，到处游泳
Everyone running, jumping, swimming with no order.
那跟乐趣差着十万八千里呢
That was the opposite of fun.
你知道什么是乐趣吗？
Do you even know what fun is?
我创造了乐趣！
I invented fun!
好吧，真是恶人当道
Boy, the wrong people get to be immortal.
看着我
Look at me.
这里的一切你都忘记了
You remember nothing of this encounter.
你对这个地方以及所遇到的怪物们毫无记忆
You have no memory of this place or the monsters you met.
现在走吧，再也别回来
Now go and never return.
等等，你说再也别回到旅社？
Wait, never return to the hotel?
什么？你应该完全不记得旅社才对啊
What? You were supposed to forget the hotel.
我施了法术除去你的记忆
I just used my powers to erase your memory.
我直直地盯着你的眼睛
I looked straight into your eyes.
哦，可能是隐形眼镜的事儿
Huh. Oh, maybe it's the contact lenses.
- 什么？ - 这些帮助我清楚地看东西的…
The what? These little plasticky doodads
…塑料小玩意儿
that help me see better.
等等，我马上拿出来给你看看
Here, let me just try and get them out real quick.
那是我见过最恶心的事没有之一！
Oh, that is the most disgusting thing I've ever seen!
- 马上就好 - 住手，拜托你住手！
Almost got it. Stop doing that. Please stop doing that!
把手指头从眼珠子上拿开！够了！
Fingers away from the eyeballs! Enough!
听着，你再也不要回来了
Listen to me. You are never to return here.
离开这儿，别跟任何人讲起这里
You are to stay away and never tell humans about this place.
否则我就吸干你的每一滴血…
Or I will track you down and suck every ounce of blood
…直到你看起来跟泄了气的气垫一样
from your body until you look like a deflated whoopee cushion!
走吧
Be gone.
想不到我就这么走了，本来一切都好好的！
Can't believe I'm leaving, man. That could have been so great!
都被那个老家伙毁了，吸干我的血
Dude ruined everything. Suck my blood.
我就该说：“我偏不走，老东西！”
I should have just said, "I'm staying, old man!"
我就应该给他来个佛山无影脚，嘭！正踢在…
Give him a Bruce Lee kick. Boom! Right in the...
上帝啊，德古拉伯爵，别杀我 我这就走，这就走
Oh, my God. Count Dracula. Please don't kill me. I'm leaving, I'm leaving.
- 跟我来 - 不行，梅薇思，我得走了
Follow me. Oh. No, no, Mavis, I can't. I have to leave.
- 你确定？很好玩的哦 - 好吧
You sure? It'll be fun. Okay.
不会被他发现吧？
He's not gonna see me, is he?
Whoa.
你想看看这上面的景色吗？
Wow, would you look at the view from up here?
- 几乎能看到布达佩斯了 - 乌…达佩斯？ （布达佩斯：匈牙利首都）
You could almost see Budapest. Who-da-pest?
在夏威力附近吗？
Is that near Ha-wi-fi?
嗯？哦，你是说夏威夷 对，那儿的景色特别迷人
Huh? Oh, you mean Hawaii. Yeah, that place is a knockout.
我刚去那儿参加了音乐节
I just went to a music festival there.
人类的音乐节吗？
A human music festival?
呃，我想是的
Uh, I believe so.
那…他们没咬你的脚趾 也没往你脸上丢涂了大蒜的面包吗？
So, did they all bite your toes and shove garlic bread in your face?
没有，不过有个家伙出人意料地…
No. Well, one dude took a bigger bite
…咬了我一大口能量棒
out of my energy bar than I expected,
但我想可能是激动所致
but I blame that on the heat.
好神奇啊，你哪儿都去过
It's amazing. You've been everywhere.
是啊，不然呢？
Well, you know, what's the alternative?
宅在家里，足不出户 永远不知道外面什么样子？
Just staying at home, never exploring, never seeing what's out there?
我只有一个121岁，不是吗？得享受生活
I'm only gonna be 121 once, right? Got to live it.
是啊
Yeah.
- 嘿，这儿的日出一定特别美… - 哎哟
Oh, man. The sunrise from here must be amaz... Ow.
哦，抱歉
Oh, I'm sorry.
小家伙，你应该从来没看过日出吧，对吗？
Man, you've probably never even seen a sunrise, have you?
恩，没看过，怎么了？
No, not really. Why?
过来，我有个主意
Come on. I have an idea.
看
Watch.
Ahh. Ahh.
我就说了你们会喜欢这儿的，是不是很爽？
Didn't I tell you guys we'd have fun in here? Is this not the best?
是啊，我出了一身汗爽透了
Yeah, I'm working up a nice sweat.
约翰那个小家伙什么时候才能搞定策划？
When's that Johnny kid gonna be done party planning?
- 他有两下子 - 是啊，能耐不小呢
He's a great hang. Yeah, he's an animal.
看到梅薇思这么开心 跟他又这么合拍简直太棒了
And it was so nice seeing Mavis laughing and hitting it off with him.
谁跟谁合拍？拜托
Who's hitting what off? Please.
梅薇思才不会跟他那种类型的合拍呢
Mavis could never be with someone of his kind.
你说什么？“他那种类型”？
I'm sorry? "His kind"?
你是说我们这一类配不上你们吗？
You're saying our kind's not good enough for you,
“阁下”？
"Your Lordship"?
不不不！弗兰克，我不是…
No, no, no! Frank, I didn't...
我是说她才不会看上那种红卷毛呢
I meant that she wouldn't be into someone with such red, curly hair.
红卷毛怎么了？
Uh, what's wrong with red, curly hair?
你不高兴什么？
Why are you getting upset?
我就是红卷毛！
I have red curly hair!
好吧，我怎么可能知道？
Well, how was I supposed to know that?
这是我见过最美的景色了
This is the most incredible thing I've ever seen.
约翰？
Johnny?
冷静，伙计们
Look, settle down, fellas.
争这个没意义，因为约翰他…已经走了
This is all a moot point because Johnny, he left.
等等，走了？
Wait a minute. He left?
对，他说他不喜欢梅薇思 也不喜欢我们任何一个
Yes. He decided he didn't like Mavis, or any of us.
嗨
Hi.
看来约翰改主意了
Hmm. I guess Johnny had second thoughts.
真不敢相信你还赖着不走，你不明白
I can't believe you stuck around, man. You don't get it.
你要有大麻烦了
Bad things are coming your way.
我得理理思路
I got to get my thoughts together.
好了
Okay.
看到这些桌子没？
You see these tables?
你今天就摆放这些桌子
You can spend the entire day pulling them out
派对策划同志
and placing them, party planner.
不错，把我困在这儿
Fantastic. I'm trapped here.
现在我算是理解你女儿的感受了
Now I know how your daughter feels.
够了！够了！停！
Enough! Enough! Stop!
到墙角去，你可以休息了！
Go to a corner, you're in a timeout!
休息？你当我是小孩吗！
Timeout? I'm a grown man!
Ahh!
好了，57号桌到23号位置去
Okay. Table 57, please move to position 23.
Whoa.
- 太酷了 - 面壁！
- That is cool. - Face the wall.
17号到48号 16号到47号 19号到50号
17 to 48. 16 to 47. 19 to 50.
- 太神奇了 - 让我安心干活
Awesomeness. Just let me do my work.
29号到35号
29 to 35.
42好到18号，10号到44号
42 to 18. 10 to 44.
17, 18, 19, 20, 21, 22, 23.
39号到24号
39 to 24.
36号飞起来！
36 up!
29号到35号
29 to 35.
Whoa!
31号到19号
31 to 19.
24号飞起来！
24 up!
7号到25号，14号到30号
Seven to 25. 14 to 30.
你要去哪儿啊，老爷爷？
Where'd you go, grandpa?
别害怕，小东西
Don't freak out, gravity face.
你根本不是我对手，老东西！
Eat my dust, gray fangs!
56号43号，到我身边来
56 and 43, to my side.
Whoo!
等着哭吧，小家伙
Prepare to cry, Billy Backpack.
我们经常这么干，半管式滑板！
That's how we do it! Half-pipe, baby!
随便
Whatever.
对，继续闻
Yes. Keep smelling.
抓到人类我们就能做人肉馅饼了
You catch the human, and then I will make human potpie!
27, 45, 65, 76，48, 堵住他的路
27, 45, 65, 76, 48, block his path.
堵住他的路！
Block his path!
Whoa-ho!
哦，来吧，臭小子！
Oh, come on now, dude man!
很好！
Nice!
Haha! Whoa-ho-ho!
我抓到你了，小子
I got you, buddy.
请勿打扰！
Do not disturb!
有人要睡觉！
People trying to sleep here!
看到没有？
Did you see that?
这是谁呀？“常散架”先生吗？
Who is that guy, Sir Breaks-a-lot?
老弟，我不得不说太有乐趣了
Oh, boy, I have to say, that was fun. Okay?
你刚才说过的那种乐趣？搞定！
The fun you were talking about earlier? Nailed it!
约翰？
Johnny?
卡西莫多！
Quasimodo!
梅薇思？你怎么还不睡 太阳出来了，会灼伤你的，小宝贝
Mavis? Why are you still up? The sun is out. It could kill you, my honeyguts.
我睡不着，你知道约翰去哪儿了吗?
I couldn't sleep. Do you know where Johnny went?
不知道，他…
I don't know. He...
- 你问这个干嘛？ - 哦，呃…
Why do you want to know? Oh! Uh...
- 你喜欢他？ - 什么？
Do you like him? What?
得了吧爸爸，他那么怪，又那么笨
Pfft, no. Come on, Dad. He's so weird and awkward.
就好比，你到底是傻呢还是没意识到自己可爱？
It's like, are you an idiot or do you know you're adorable?
呃，等会儿
Eh... Hold that.
- 知道卡西莫多的确切位置吗？ - 知道
Do you have a location on Quasimodo? Yes, sir.
他们正穿过大堂朝厨房走去
They're heading through the lobby, towards the kitchen.
我要他们立刻停下来
I need them stopped immediately.
- 明白我的意思吗？ - 明白
Is that clear? Yes, quite.
马上就办
We are on it.
啊哈，没抓到！
Ha-ha! Missed!
这什么意思？让我过去！
What is the meaning of this? Let me pass!
卡西莫多·威尔逊，你得跟我们走
Quasimodo Wilson, you are coming with us.
我怎么会疼呢？
Why did that hurt me?
听着宝贝，你还小，不适合谈恋爱
Look, honey, there's no falling in love at your age.
妈妈也是我这么大 尤尼斯阿姨说是妈妈先亲你的
Mom was my age. Eunice says Mom kissed you first
因为你不敢迈出第一步
'cause you were too scared to make the first move.
是是是是是
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
别再提我和妈妈还有什么接吻了
Forget about me and Mom and kissing.
爸爸，总有一天我要结婚的
Dad, at some point, I'm going to get married.
- 我不可能永远待在这儿 - 什么？为什么不能？
I can't be here forever. What? Why not?
你牙才刚长齐
You're barely out of your training fangs.
Ha-ha!
我又赢了！
Quasi wins again!
班门弄斧，自取其辱！
When you bump with the hump, you land on your rump!
你怎么突然对这个感兴趣了呢？
But why all the sudden interest?
我们每次谈起“爱”时，你总是说…
Every time we used to talk about love, it was always,
“哦爸爸，真恶心”
"Ooh, Dad, that's gross,"
不然就是“哦爸爸，我不想听这些”
and "Ooh, Dad, I don't want to know about that."
我不知道
I don't know.
- 大人，他进入厨房了 - 什么？
Sir, he made it into the kitchen. He what?
我花钱雇你吃干饭的吗？
What do I pay you for?
抱歉宝贝，我得先走了
I'm sorry, honey. I have to go.
他没给我钱
He doesn't pay me.
你杀了我之前…
Before you kill me,
…能让我再跟我的背包说句话吗？
can I please talk to my backpack one more time?
我不想带着遗憾走
I don't want to leave anything unresolved.
你好，德古拉先生！
Bonjour, Monsieur Dracula!
闭上你那臭嘴
Shut your hump hole.
你为什么要帮他？
Now you are helping him?
你跟这个人类的臭小子之间有什么勾当？
What is it with you and this human?
他不是人类，他是斯坦家族的一员！
He is not human. He's a Stein!
对，小矮子，我是斯坦族一员！
That's right, little man, I'm a Stein!
他要是怪物，就让他吓吓艾丝美拉达！
If he is a monster, let him scare Esmeralda!
那只耗子？
The mouse?
切，小意思
Pfft! Without a doubt.
好吧，看好了
Okay. Here we go.
Blargh!
Bleegh!
Blargy-bliggy-blargh!
人！人！
A human! A human!
德古拉把人带进…
Monsieur Dracula has brought a human into the...
艾丝美拉达，帮帮我
Esmeralda, help me.
谢谢你救我
Hey, thanks for saving me back there.
那家伙疯了，他要吃我！
That guy's crazy! Trying to eat me.
这种事只发生过一次 活结乐队的演唱会上有个怪胎也想这么干
That's only happened to me one other time. This weird dude at a Slipknot concert.
我要给你看个东西
There's something I need to show you.
Wow.
嘿，我们是在参加葬礼吗？
Hey, are we at a funeral right now?
哦，等等，不，这是你的床
Oh, wait, no, it's your bed.
酷毙了
So creepy and cool.
喔！我知道她！
Wow! I know her!
我在爱之堡废墟见过那幅画，我最爱的城堡
I've seen that picture at the ruins of Lubov. That's my favorite castle.
那儿流传着一个关于那个女人的传说
There's a whole legend around that lady.
传说？
A legend?
爱之女神
The Lady Lubov.
故事中一位孤单的伯爵跟她邂逅…
The story is that a lonely count
…据说他们两人心心相印…
met her by chance, and they say that no two souls
…你侬我侬…
were ever more meant for each other.
最后他们在爱之堡定居下来，还生了个小宝宝
Eventually, they settled down at Castle Lubov and had a child.
就在那时，悲剧发生了
But then, a horrible tragedy happened.
一天晚上莫名起火，把他们都烧死了
A fire started mysteriously one night, and it killed both of them.
我置身城堡时，还能感受到他们爱的力量
When I was at the castle, I could still feel their powerful love.
人们说似乎仍有灵魂困在废墟之中
They say it's as if a soul is still trapped in the ruins themselves.
传说弄错了
The legend is wrong.
只有妻子死了
It was only the wife that died.
Oh.
她也不是死于什么不明大火
And it was no mystery who killed her.
是你们人类烧死了她！
She was killed by your kind!
吸血鬼！
Vampire!
- 亲爱的 - 快走，这里交给我
Honey? Go hide. I'll take care of this.
吸血鬼！
Vampire!
玛莎！
Martha!
他们才是真正的怪物
They are the real monsters.
我为我的爱人建了这座城堡，来保护她的孩子
I built this place for my love, to protect her child.
作为父亲，你必须竭尽全力保护全家的安全
As a father, you do everything to keep your family safe,
哪怕是以欺骗为代价
even if you have to break their trust.
可现在，梅薇思对你有了感觉
But now, Mavis has feelings for you.
什么？
What?
我只是…
I just...
- 真没想到 - 没错
Awesome. It's all right.
你是个不错的小伙
You are a good one.
要是世道变了，你们或许还有可能
If the world was different, maybe it would be possible.
德古，现在都21世纪了
Drac, this is the 21st century.
人们跟以前已经大不一样
People aren't the same as they were back then.
你确定如果我们公开身份…
Can you tell me for certain that if we came out in the open,
…大家都能接纳我们吗？
everyone would accept us?
每个人？
Everyone?
不，你说得对
No. You're right.
我这次真走了
I'll go for good this time.
你可以说我有急事儿
You can just say I had some emergency,
要么就说我被小精灵夫人吃掉了吧
or the gremlin lady ate me or something.
不不不，不不
No, no, no, no, no.
我不想毁了她的生日派对
I don't want to ruin her birthday party.
你可以在派对结束后偷偷溜走
You can sneak out after it's all done.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我最不想做的事就是伤害她
The last thing I wanted was to hurt her.
还有你
Or you.
知道吗，你科学怪人扮得实在不怎么样
You know, you're not the smoothest Frankenstein,
但或许扮演吸血鬼会很棒
but you'd make a great vampire.
真的？
For real?
可能是因为我学会了你那双催眠眼
'Cause I think I kind of got your hypno-eyes down.
小家伙，来吧，演一个我看看
Oh, boy, here we go. Let me see it.
当心！我已经对你施了魔法
Beware! For you are in my power.
我要你变成狼人！
I command you to be the werewolf man!
我孩子太多了
I have too many kids.
给我挠挠，我长虱子了
Someone scratch me, I have fleas.
他是狼人，会长虱子
'Cause he's a wolf, he'd get those.
得啦，别解释了
Yeah, no, don't explain it.
解释了就不好玩了
It's not funny when you do that.
我没要求叫醒服务
I didn't order a wake-up call.
德古拉伯爵给每个房间都安排了叫醒服务
Count Dracula arranged it for all the rooms.
止闹按钮在哪儿？
Where's the snooze button?
今天不能止闹，生日趴就在今天
There will be no snoozing. The party's today.
不错，好极了
Ooh, yeah, perfecto.
118岁生日快乐 妈妈
# 姑娘 #
# 不敢相信这是你的狂欢之夜 #
# 你开始吃青蛙，正是派对的好时候 #
# 时光都溜去了哪儿啊，姑娘 #
# 姑娘，曾经你还叼着奶嘴儿 #
# 看看现在 #
# 你已能直接吸牛的血 #
Wow.
你可真漂亮
You look beautiful.
谢谢，谢谢你为我办派对
Thanks. Thanks for the party.
喜欢我的小花招吗？
Yeah, you like my little touches?
巴黎
纽约
莫斯科
夏威威
太神奇了
It's amazing.
- 派对棒极了 - 你太能干了，德古拉
Terrific party. You really outdid yourself, Drac.
这是我500年来参加的最棒的派对了
Got to be the best one I've been to in 500 years.
抱歉，大个子
Sorry, big man.
呃，梅薇思？
Uh, Mavis?
我现在害怕极了
I'm crazily scared right now.
也许是个好事儿
Maybe that's a good thing.
你怎么能干出这种事儿？ 在我跟你分享了我的痛苦之后？
How could you? After I shared my pain with you?
- 但不是… - 爸爸，不过是接个吻而已
But, no... Dad, it was just a kiss.
不，你不可以接吻
No, you're not allowed to kiss.
爸爸，我可以，我不是83岁的小孩了
Dad, I'm allowed to do things. I'm not 83 any more.
我可以有心上人 或许还可以再去外面的世界瞧瞧
I'm allowed to like people, or go see the world again.
什么？你已经看过了！你说你一点儿也不喜欢！
What? You saw it! You said you didn't like it!
也许我可以再给那个村子一次机会
Maybe I want to give the village another chance.
我只是需要学习，学习随机应变，像约翰那样
I just need to learn, you know, just how to roll with it, like Johnny does.
不不，你不能再去那个村子了
No, no, you can't go to the village again.
说不定你可以证明给他们看，我们能够成为朋友
Maybe you can make them see that we could be friends.
不，那不可能
No, that isn't possible.
别说那么肯定，这完全取决于你如何表现
Well, you can't be sure. It's all in how you present yourself.
- 不，根本没用 - 你怎么知道？
No, that won't make a difference! How do you know?
- 就是没用！ - 为什么？为什么没用？
Because it just won't! Why? Why won't it?
因为那个村子根本就不存在！
Because that village doesn't really exist!
什么叫“不存在”？
What do you mean "doesn't exist"?
你做了什么？
What did you do?
做我该做的
I did what I had to do.
到底是什么？
What was it?
什么是你该做的？告诉我！
What exactly did you have to do? Tell me!
我…我建了那个村子，都是我建的
I... I built the town. The staff put it all together.
僵尸们扮演了村民
The zombies dressed up as the townspeople.
别生气，我…
Please. I...
如果你真在外面遇到什么危险
If you really went out there and something happened to you,
我无法原谅自己
I just couldn't live with myself.
你就能原谅自己这么做？对我撒撒谎？骗我？
But you can live with this? Lying to me? Tricking me?
明知道我梦想着离开却要永远把我关在这里？
Keeping me here forever when you knew my dream was to go.
骗子！骗子！
Liar! Liar!
老油子？
Oil?
Uh-uh-uh!
请说英语
English, please.
你的声音真的很聒噪
Your voice is really annoying.
等等，我懂他意思
Wait, I speak frozen.
他说：“德古拉带了个人类到旅社里”
He says, "Dracula has brought a human into the hotel."
- 人类？ - 抱紧我，亲爱的！
A human? Stay close, pookie!
他说：“他就是涅个人类”
He says, "There is ze human."
他有法国口音
He has a French accent.
约翰不是人类，他是跟我右手有血亲的堂弟
Johnny's not a human. He's my right arm's cousin.
- 他撒谎 - 对
- He's lying. - Yeah.
他为什么戳着鼻孔？
And why is he picking his nose?
他说：“说来话长”
He says, "it's a long story."
嘿，等等，别！离我远点！
Hey, wait, no! Get off me!
Ew!
他说：“看吧，人类”
He says, "Behold ze human."
真不敢相信
I don't believe it.
真的吗？你是人类？
Is it true? Are you a human?
是
Yes.
非常抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我不在乎，我还是要跟你在一起
I don't care. I still want to be with you.
Uh...
可是，我不想跟你在一起
Well, tough. 'Cause I don't want to be with you.
因为你是个怪物，我讨厌怪物
Because you're a monster. And I hate monsters.
再见
Goodbye.
请别伤害我！
Please don't hurt me!
都是你的错！
This is all your fault!
- 我们要离开这儿 - 我再也不会回来了
We're getting out of here. I'm never coming back here.
我早就闻到人味儿了，“绝无人类”？开什么玩笑
I thought I smelt a human. "Human-free"? What a rip.
他来了，德“枯”拉伯爵
Oh. Here he comes. Count Crock-ula.
真庆幸我眼睛瞎了，我可不想…
I'm just glad my eyes are stitched shut, 'cause I don't even want to...
梅薇思，宝贝，你在吗？
Mavis, honey, are you in there?
梅薇思？梅薇思？
Mavis? Mavis?
梅薇思，你在哪儿？
Mavis, where are you?
梅薇思？
Mavis?
爸爸，能帮我个忙吗？
Dad, can you do me a favor?
能，当然能亲爱的，什么忙都行
Yes, yes, of course, darling. Anything.
你能消除我的记忆吗？
Will you erase my mind?
不不不，不行，我不会这么做的
No, no, no, no. No, I won't do that.
有太多我想让你记住的事儿了
There's too much I want you to remember.
你说得对，爸爸，人类讨厌我们
You were right, Dad. The humans hate us.
宝贝儿，世上有很多不错的怪物男孩
Sweetheart, there are so many eligible monsters out there.
你还太年轻…
You're so young to...
这是什么？你在读什么？
What is it? What are you reading?
真爱 妈妈著
为你的118岁生日
<i>两只孤单的蝙蝠在夜里相遇</i>
"Two lonely bats crashed in the night."
<i>他们彼此“心动”，一见钟情</i>
"They felt a Zing. Love at first sight."
<i>就在那时，他们便知道彼此会结为夫妻</i>
"They knew right then they would be husband and wife."
<i>因为一生只会有一次“心动”</i>
"For a Zing only happens once in your life."
<i>你也会“心动”的，我的宝贝儿</i>
"Your Zing will come, my love."
<i>珍惜吧</i>
"Cherish it."
<i>爱你的，妈妈</i>
"Love, Mommy."
- 我以为我们心动了，爸爸 - 你跟约翰？
- I thought we Zinged, Dad. - You and Johnny?
我想只是我自己动了心
I guess it was only me.
但你应该高兴，爸爸
But you should be happy, Dad.
我再也没有理由离开了
There's no reason for me to leave.
我的心已经死了，我现在跟你一样了
I have no more dreams. I'm just like you now.
天堂，夏威夷应有尽有
玛莎，我都干了什么啊？
Martha, what have I done?
- 我的账单呢？ - 在这儿，我是下一个
Where is my bill? Over here. I'm next.
- 我要退房 - 给你钥匙！给你！
I'm checking out. Take my key! Take my key!
迷你冰箱的费用哪儿来的？
What is this minibar charge?
亲爱的，孩子们把迷你冰箱扔出窗外了
Honey, the kids threw the minibar out the window.
- 那是我们的错吗？ - 呃…
And that's our fault? Well...
借过，不好意思！
Excuse me! Pardon, yeah.
不好意思，有几个人要寄快递
Excuse me, I got a couple of people to express mail.
朋友们，拜托，停下来
Friends, please, stop.
太晚了，死蝙蝠！
It's too late, rat-bat!
拜托，我求你们了
Please, I'm begging you.
我需要你们帮我找到约翰
I need you to help me find Johnny.
那个人类？他差点儿杀了我们！
The human? He could've killed us!
他碰了我的吉他！
He touched my guitar!
他把手伸进我嘴里看会不会消失
He put his hand in my mouth to see if it would disappear.
他还让我吃了他的滑板车！
He let me eat his scooter!
我知道我撒了谎
I know I lied.
我错了
I was wrong.
但你们要相信
But you have to believe this:
约翰不是个坏人
Johnny wasn't a bad guy.
事实上，我都不确信人类是否还像以前那么坏了
The truth is, I don't even know if humans are bad any more.
弗兰克，别这样，老兄，你懂的
Frank, come on, buddy. You understand.
他不会再跟你说话了
He's not talking to you.
你先告诉我们人类很坏，现在又说他们好了
First you tell us humans are bad, now they're good.
还有什么？上下颠倒，冷热不分，小精灵也不臭烘烘了
What else? Up is down, cold is hot, gremlins don't smell.
嘿
Hey!
不管是不是我的堂弟，我都真心喜欢约翰 他会讲有趣的故事
I really liked Johnny, cousin or no. He told fun stories.
我想他们彼此心动了
I think they Zinged.
他们心动了？
They Zinged?
但是我却横加干预
But I got in the way.
一生只有一次心动
You only Zing once in your life.
- 喂，你大脑短路了 - 我不在乎
Oy, now you're short-circuiting. I don't care!
你们还磨蹭什么呢？我们去找约翰，快！
Well, what are we doing? Let's get Johnny. Come on!
- 对，去找约翰！ - 快点！
Yeah, let's do it! Come on!
Yeah!
我们本该在你父母家度蜜月的！
We should have honeymooned at your parents!
好吧，我该去哪儿？
Okay, okay, where am I going?
去人类世界啊，赶在约翰永远离开之前
The human world, before Johnny's gone forever.
可现在有太阳怎么办？
But what about the sun?
不知道，我想只能随机应变了
I don't know. I'll just have to roll.
他刚随机应变了，现在他会这招了
He just rolls. Rollability.
我们要跟着他的脚印
So we follow his boot-prints.
脚印没了，就要靠你了，维恩
When they run out, that's where you come in, Wayne.
- 我？ - 那儿！
Me? There!
我就知道他那背包里得掉东西
Yes, I knew something would fall out of that backpack.
臭死了！
Yowch! That stinks!
大显身手吧
Work your magic.
等等，你让我跟踪他的气味？
Wait, you want me to track the smell?
得了吧，我的嗅觉早就不灵了
No. My sniffing tracking days are way behind me.
你知道我换了多少尿布吗？
Do you know how many diapers I've changed?
多少大便都把这玩意儿毁了？
How many number twos have destroyed this thing?
不过…
But...
嘿！别紧张！小心！
Hey! Take it easy! Watch it!
坐下
Sit.
闻！我让你闻！
Smell. I said smell.
没让你闻我，闻衬衫！衬衫！
Not me, the shirt! The shirt!
你的孩子还有听你话的吗？
Do any of your kids still respect you?
嗯，等我想想，哦对了
Mm, give me a second. Oh, yeah.
维妮！到前面来！
Winnie! Front and center!
他上了一辆车，86年产的菲亚特
He got into a car. A '86 Fiat.
那辆车变速器需要修修，不过不修也行
It needs a little transmission work, but otherwise okay.
它穿过城镇去了机场，497次航班
It drove through town to the airport. Flight 497.
早上八点起飞
8:00 a.m. departure.
就剩15分钟了
That's in 15 minutes.
座位是23A
Seat 23A.
他订的是素餐
He ordered the vegetarian meal.
好的，谢谢你，小可爱
Okay, thank you, cutie.
现在你们都给我回到妈妈身边去！
Now, all of you, go back to your mother!
有羊！
Sheep!
击掌庆祝吧！没人理我吗
High five! Don't leave me hanging.
- 好多羊 - 我来
Lots of sheep! I got this one.
怎么样？没有羊挡路了，走吧
What? Now there's no sheep in the road. Let's go.
太恶心了，老兄
That was pretty sick, man.
你也吃羊排，没什么两样
You eat lamb chops, it's the same thing.
我们没时间纠结这个，快点，开车！
We don't have time for this. Come on, let's move it!
看，有个人
Look, a human.
欢迎来到特兰西瓦尼亚！ （罗马尼亚地名，相传为“吸血鬼之乡”）
Welcome to Transylvania!
我有点晕
That was trippy.
怪物嘉年华？
Monster Festival?
怪物嘉年华是什么玩意？
What's a Monster Festival?
我们爱德古拉
我们为科学怪人高举火把
他们早知道我们要来？
Did they know we were coming?
他们喜欢我们？
They like us?
真的吗？
Really?
打扰一下，你知道怎么去机场最方便吗？
Excuse me? Do you know the best way to the airport?
知道，德古拉老弟，只有一条路，吧啦吧啦吧啦
Yes, fellow Dracula. There's only one way. Bleh, bleh-bleh.
但都被疯了，我们没法及时赶到的
But it's all blocked. We'll never make it in time.
你应该提前一个小时出来的，吧啦吧啦吧啦
You should have left an hour earlier. Bleh, bleh-bleh.
我从没那么说过，“吧啦吧啦吧啦”
I do not say "Bleh, bleh-bleh."
好吧，我们跑过去好了
All right, let's just run through it on foot.
德古拉，这个能保护你
Drac, this'll protect you.
吧啦吧啦吧啦
Bleh, bleh-bleh.
你猜那家伙要知道他在跟真正的德古拉说话会怎样
Imagine if that guy knew he was talking to the real Drac.
他会跑得远远的！
He'd run for the hills!
等一下，等一下
Hold it, now. Hold it, now.
好像说到点儿上了
That sounds spot on.
但只有我们告诉他们，他们才能知道咱是真的
But the only way they'd know the real us is if we show the real us.
这办法不错
This could work.
你是说吓唬他们？我们几百年没吓过人了
You mean, like, scare them? We haven't scared people in centuries.
我甚至怀疑自己还会不会吓唬人了
I don't even think I have it in me any more.
我不会了，我真不会了
I got nothing. I really got nothing.
只要用这个就行了
Let's just move this along.
火！火！
Fire! Fire!
火！
Fire!
我在吓唬你们！
I'm trying to scare you!
真正的科学怪人！
The real Frankenstein!
我们知道，我们爱你
We know! We love you!
能在我的火把上签个名吗？
Can you sign my torch?
听着，首先我得告诉你们 下面那位是真正的德古拉！
Listen, before anything else, down there's the real Dracula!
怎么证明？
Prove it.
好吧，继续
All right. Continue.
德古拉的女儿坠入了爱河，而他要赶去机场！
Drac's daughter's in love, and he's got to get to the airport!
但他没法穿越人群！
And he can't get through this crowd!
- 他怎么不飞呢？ - 有太阳啊，笨蛋，他是吸血鬼
Why doesn't he fly? The sun, you idiot. He's a vampire.
说得对，谢谢提醒，书呆子怪物
That's right. Thank you, Monster Nerd.
所以，要是你们真拿我们当朋友 请给他让出一条路来！
So, people, if you really are our friends, clear a path for the man!
好吧，吸血鬼们，列队，吧啦吧啦吧啦
Okay. All Draculas, line up. Bleh, bleh-bleh.
其他人拉起斗篷，保护我们的朋友
Everyone else, lift the capes. Protect our friend. Bleh, bleh-bleh.
都是为了你啊，老兄
It's all for you, buddy.
去吧
Go ahead.
- 祝你好运！ - 去找到他们！
Good luck! Go get 'em!
去吧，德古，快！
Go, Drac, go!
- 去吧，德古！ - 去吧，德古！
Go, Drac! Go, Drac!
去吧，德古！
Go, Drac!
去找到他们！
Go get 'em!
去吧，德古拉，快！
Go, Drac, go!
我们爱你，德古拉！
We love you, Dracula!
别无选择了
There's no choice.
Ouch. Ouch, ouch, ouch.
好吧，我必须得这么做
Okay. Okay, I must do this.
约翰森，约翰森，能听见吗？
Jonathan. Jonathan, can you hear me?
告诉我，你想当吸血鬼吗？
Tell me, do you dream of being a vampire?
他们就是这么描述我们的，真难想象
This is how we're represented. Unbelievable.
约翰森，约翰森
Jonathan. Jonathan.
能听见我说话吗？
Can you hear me?
喔！蝙蝠！
Whoa! Bat!
等等，它在说话，德古拉，是你吗？
Wait, it's talking. Dracula? Is that you?
呃？德古拉
Huh? Dracula.
我听不清
I can't understand you.
什么？我的手在棕色皮鞋里？
What? My hand's in a tan shoe?
什么？日本人吃炖羊肉？
What? Japan's eating lamb stew?
嘿，你知道自己在冒烟吗？
Hey, do you know you're smoking?
哦
Oh.
对不起，抱歉
Pardon me. Sorry, excuse me.
啊，不好意思
Whoa! Excuse me.
- 这是什么鬼东西？ - 蝙蝠怎么能飞得这么高？
What the heck? How'd a bat get up this high?
乘客朋友们，我们打开安全带指示灯，以防…
Folks, I'm gonna turn on the seat belt sign. Just a precaution while we...
<i>听到一个给我亲爱的朋友约翰森的特殊公告</i>
While we hear a special announcement for my dear friend Jonathan.
德古拉？
Dracula?
我亲爱的孩子，我犯了一个严重的错误
My dear boy, I have made a terrible mistake.
我妄图把宝贝女儿拴在自己身边
I was trying to keep my baby to myself,
因为我知道我可以一直保护她
because I knew I would always protect her.
但我现在意识到，孩子们需要自己去探索
But I realize now, children need to discover things for themselves.
他们会跌倒，会摔跤，会笑也会哭
They'll stumble and fall, laugh and cry,
可这就是生活
but such is life.
事实上，你跟梅薇思是天生一对
The truth is, you and Mavis are meant to be.
你们一见钟情
You Zinged.
如果她一定要爱上什么人
If she must give her trust to someone else,
我很庆幸那个人是你，约翰森
I'm thankful that it is you, Jonathan.
希望你能听见我的话，并原谅我
I hope you can hear me and forgive me-
好了，乘客朋友们，我们马上掉头回去加油
Okay, folks, we're going to make a quick turnaround to refuel,
之后将恢复正常飞行
and then we'll be back on our way.
别哭了，我身上都着火了！
Quit your whining! I'm burning up out here!
爸爸？
Dad?
我没事，就是有点晒伤
I'm fine. I'm just a little sunburnt.
亲爱的
Honey,
我总以为最糟糕的事就是看到你离我而去
I always thought the worst thing ever would be seeing you go.
但其实，最糟糕的是看到你不开心
But the worst is seeing you unhappy.
梅薇，希望你能有自己的生活
Mavey, I want you to live your life.
我不知道该怎么做
I don't know how I'm supposed to do that.
你看，妈妈已经给了你她的生日礼物
You know, Mommy already gave you her birthday present.
现在给你我的礼物好吗？
Can I now give you mine?
我要这个有什么用？
What do I need this for?
哈，它还有个赠品
Oh, it comes with an accessory.
- 是你？ - 是你
You? You.
你怎么回来了？
Why are you back?
因为你是我的心上人，梅维思
'Cause you're my Zing, Mavis.
我是你的心上人？
I'm your Zing?
可你说你讨厌怪物
But you told me you hate monsters.
好吧，我是怕要是不那么说…
Yeah, well, I was afraid your dad was gonna
…你爸爸会吸干我的血
suck all the blood out of my body if I didn't say that.
我才不会…
I wouldn't have...
不，他说得对，我会那么干的
No, he's right, I would have done that.
- 爸爸 - 我错了，小坏蛋
Dad. I was wrong, Devil-chops.
天堂 夏威夷应有尽有
你说真的吗，爸爸？
Do you really mean it, Dad?
去创造属于自己的天堂吧
Go make your own paradise.
我们可以试着再接一次吻吗？
Can we try that kiss over again?
我想可以
I think we can.
对不起，我只是…我想我得学着习惯这个
Sorry. I just... I got to get used to that.
继续，你们继续
Go. Do your thing.
祝梅微思生日快乐
停！停！
Stop! Stop!
# 我曾以为找到了真爱，她却是玩玩而已 #
# 后来我遇见一个女孩，心生别样情愫 #
# 那感觉像被击中，不由自主地心动 #
# 浓浓爱意让我快要无法呼吸 #
# 那感觉是一见钟情，我想唱给你听 #
# 听听那小调儿，它唱的是斯汀 #
# 凝望你的眼睛，仿佛春天悄然来临 #
# 就像狮子王中娜娜看着辛巴的眼睛 #
# 爱情就这样在不知不觉中悄然降临 #
# 我在爱情海上空恣意翱翔 #
# 风雨中相爱如今已忘了伤痛 #
# 此刻让我们举杯欢庆 #
# 因为你是我的真命天子 #
德古，你准备加入我们吗？
Drac, you ready to throw down?
不不，我只是离近点儿好听清楚
No, no, I just came closer to hear you better.
来吧，来试试
Come on, just give it a try.
好吧，就试一下下
All right, maybe just a little.
# 五湖四海的恋人们，请你们都听清 #
# 掀翻床垫尽情迎接美好的爱情 #
# 如果爱是金钱，马上你们要收不停 #
# 丘比特的箭射来得有点像蜜蜂叮 #
# 我想这种感觉就是所谓一见钟情 #
# 大千世界我只对她钟情 #
# 因为当你为爱倾心 #
# 要知道你唯一需要准备的 #
#就是戒指一枚亮晶晶 #
# 爱情在空气中弥漫 #
# 我不顾一切 #
# 在爱情海里自由翱翔 #
# 风雨中相爱如今已忘了伤痛 #
# 此刻让我们举杯欢庆 #
# 我们的爱是命中注定 #
# 尽情去爱 #
# 那枚戒指让你震惊 #
# 最好带着它，有喜事来临 #
# 小心我这个不死之王 #
# 我是怪物 我是怪怪物 #
打扫房间！
Housekeeping!
谢谢观赏TLF字幕
TLF中文字幕站欢迎你 http://sub.eastgame.org/
我什么都没干
I didn't do that.